<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2025 RevMetrix on Hugo Relearn Theme</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2025 RevMetrix on Hugo Relearn Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Backend</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/backend/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/backend/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;database&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview: The Revmetrix project seeks to provide comprehensive tools for bowlers and researchers who can use the provided metrics to improve their game or study the physics of bowling. These tools provided to the end user take the form of the Ball Spinner Application and the Mobile Application, both of which require a database schema to serve the goals of the project. The Ball Spinner application schema is tailored for researchers aiming to refine the algorithms that generate bowling metrics, with a focus on simulated shot data collected through the BSA. In contrast, the Mobile Application schema emphasizes usability and game tracking, offering data more relevant to a bowler’s personal performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ball Spinner Application</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/frontend/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/frontend/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ball-spinner-application-overview&#34;&gt;Ball Spinner Application Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Ball Spinner Application (BSA) is to provide an interface for controlling and receiving data from the Ball Spinner as well as the SmartDot.
Ball Spinner data, along with user related data used to facilitate Simulated Shots with the Ball Spinner, is also saved to the cloud database.
Users are provided with a streamlined view (Figure 1) that displays all relevant data received during a shot. This includes a graphical representation of incoming SmartDot data, as well as a simulation that visually displays the movement of the ball as it spins in the Ball Spinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ball Spinner Controller</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/bsc/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/bsc/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ball Spinner Controller (BSC) acts as intermediary between Ball Spinner Application (BSA) and Ball Spinner
Data from Sensors is sent to the BSA and graphed against simulated data of the expected sensor data
Human Machine Interface (HMI) is 7” touch screen interaction assistant, standalone driver, and debugger for the BSC.
The HMI can be run in local mode and control all hardware within the BSC
The HMI can also graph and display the sensor data&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballspinner Physical Design</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-system&#34;&gt;Physical System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of the Ball Spinner Team was to create a testing apparatus capable of spinning a bowling ball along multiple axes of rotation in a controlled manner. This controlled spinning is designed to mimic the forces experienced during a shot down the lane, which is used to benchmark and calibrate the SmartDot sensor readings within the Ball’s insert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/1.png?width=40vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Backend Arch&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 40vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;proposed-system&#34;&gt;Proposed System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1st Axis
Relies on a vice grip system with lock nuts to induce a clamping force to prevent slippage.
Driven by gear and chain
2nd Axis
Rotates the previous sub-system utilizing a direct drive motor paired with a lazy susan to pivot up to 90 degrees in either lateral direction
3rd Axis
Directly driven to tilt the previous sub-systems up to 45 degrees in either direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Application</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;mobile-application-overview&#34;&gt;Mobile Application Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the mobile application is to provide users with an intuitive way to record and view their bowling performance data.
The application allows users to store and manage a variety of data, including Events, Sessions, Games, Frames, Shots, Bowling Establishments, Bowling Balls, and Account information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/1.png?width=20vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Backend Arch&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 20vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/2.png?width=40vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Backend Arch&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 40vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shot-page&#34;&gt;Shot Page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shot page is the base of the mobile application. It contains a frame view at the top to show the pins knocked down on each shot, as well as the game’s score. Below that, there are buttons and input fields used to track a full game of bowling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>