<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2025 RevMetrix on Hugo Relearn Theme</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2025 RevMetrix on Hugo Relearn Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Backend</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/backend/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/backend/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;database&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview: The Revmetrix project seeks to provide comprehensive tools for bowlers and researchers who can use the provided metrics to improve their game or study the physics of bowling. These tools provided to the end user take the form of the Ball Spinner Application and the Mobile Application, both of which require a database schema to serve the goals of the project. The Ball Spinner application schema is tailored for researchers aiming to refine the algorithms that generate bowling metrics, with a focus on simulated shot data collected through the BSA. In contrast, the Mobile Application schema emphasizes usability and game tracking, offering data more relevant to a bowler’s personal performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ball Spinner Application</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/frontend/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/frontend/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ball-spinner-application-overview&#34;&gt;Ball Spinner Application Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Ball Spinner Application (BSA) is to provide an interface for controlling and receiving data from the Ball Spinner as well as the SmartDot.
Ball Spinner data, along with user related data used to facilitate Simulated Shots with the Ball Spinner, is also saved to the cloud database.
Users are provided with a streamlined view (Figure 1) that displays all relevant data received during a shot. This includes a graphical representation of incoming SmartDot data, as well as a simulation that visually displays the movement of the ball as it spins in the Ball Spinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ball Spinner Controller</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/bsc/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/bsc/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ball Spinner Controller (BSC) acts as intermediary between Ball Spinner Application (BSA) and Ball Spinner
Data from Sensors is sent to the BSA and graphed against simulated data of the expected sensor data
Human Machine Interface (HMI) is 7” touch screen interaction assistant, standalone driver, and debugger for the BSC.
The HMI can be run in local mode and control all hardware within the BSC
The HMI can also graph and display the sensor data&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballspinner Physical Design</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-system&#34;&gt;Physical System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/1.png?width=40vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Backend Arch&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 40vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploded View of the Physical Model:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x 2”x4”x36” wood blocks used to support the ball and house the bearings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x plywood pieces to mount motor and serve as base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x steel axle rod 0.8” OD ± 0.01”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra material serves as minor counterweight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Axle rod to be threaded for vice handle and lock nut clamping mechanism (future Implementation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x 34Y307D-LW8 NEMA 34 stepper motor w/ a E5-500-394-I-D D-G-B motor encoder mounted onto the rear
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mounted using aluminum faceplates that screw into the wood block faces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resting on top vibration dampening, foam, material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizes a padded shim to offset motor tilt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-D printed cups are sized to house the foam ball and hold it in place using screws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The physical model is constructed using two pieces of wood measuring 3.5”x1.5”x36” and two plywood pieces to serve as base and motor mount. The vice axle (left) side is made using a steel rod machined down to 0.8” OD ± 0.01” so as to fit within the single bearing mounted within the vice axle side. The extra length of the axle rod serves as a minor counterweight and will be threaded to mount a vice handle lock nut system, future implementation, this axle feeds through the bearing and into the cup which it is then locked into. The motor on top is a 34Y307D-LW8 NEMA 34 stepper motor with a E5-500-394-I-D-D-G-B encoder mounted onto the rear. The motor rests on a piece of dampening material (foam) and is mounted to the system by using an aluminum face-plate which is screwed onto the system and face of the motor. The motor is geared using a 1.25:1 ratio and connected to the motor axle via chain, which is held taught by chain tensioners mounted below the face plate. The motor axle is constructed using a dowel rod that was sanded and modified to fit the bearings that are both mounted within the motor side of the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/1.jpg?width=40vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Backend Arch&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 40vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side View of the Physical Model Showing the Chain Assembly: The exposed chain measures around 40” in length when unlinked and connects a 6” OD 3 teeth/inch spur gear to a ~4.8” OD 3 teeth/inch spur gear. This results in a 1.25:1 gearing ratio that is driven via the stepper motor. Chain tensioners are implemented to keep the chain action smooth and consistent, especially since this axis will experience the highest level of rotation and is not currently guarded outside of the enclosure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/ballspinner/5.png?width=40vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Backend Arch&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 40vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motor Mounting Plate:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cloud/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cloud/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;publishing-nuget-packages&#34;&gt;Publishing Nuget Packages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuget is a package repository provided by Microsoft for .NET projects. It integrates very nicely with Github such that users can publish Nuget packages to a specific Github repo-sitory. This also enables permission-specific downloads related to NuGet packages, so no one outside of the Github organization can download or make changes to the Nuget package. For the RevMetrix project, we have our own Nuget package called RevMetrix.Ballspinner.Common.API. This package contains all classes defined within the Common module within the BallSpinner-Cloud repository:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cloud/1.png?width=40vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Backend Arch&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 40vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Common module contains all of the POCO (standing for Plain Old Class Object) classes that are used for client-side/server-side ORM (object relational mapping). That is why we publish it as a Nuget package, so that the client-side ORM can match that of the server. This allows for consistency in terms of the database objects being sent to and from the server and also further simplifies API migrations that can easily be updated client-side through the Nuget package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Application</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/index.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;mobile-application-overview&#34;&gt;Mobile Application Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the mobile application is to provide users with an intuitive way to record and view their bowling performance data.
The application allows users to store and manage a variety of data, including Events, Sessions, Games, Frames, Shots, Bowling Establishments, Bowling Balls, and Account information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/mobile_mainpage_default.jpg?width=20vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Main Page Default&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 20vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/2025-capstone/cureent-state-of-revmetrix/cellular/mobile_mainpage_loggedin.jpg?width=20vw&amp;amp;lightbox=false&#34; alt=&#34;Main Page Logged In&#34; class=&#34;figure-image noborder nolightbox noshadow&#34; style=&#34;height: auto; width: 20vw;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shot-page&#34;&gt;Shot Page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shot page is the base of the mobile application. It contains a frame view at the top to show the pins knocked down on each shot, as well as the game’s score. Below that, there are buttons and input fields used to track a full game of bowling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>